Geoffrey Bergeret French Nationality 29 years old

Cloud/DevSecOps/Infrastructure Engineer

« Single Responsibility Principle »

+44 7871 334653 job@gbergeret.com www.gbergeret.org

Profile

By experience I acquired variety of skills in several area like: Software, System, Security, Network and Cloud. Now my focus is to support businesses from early stage to nail their Infrastructure and CI/CD pipeline while improving their DevSecOps culture. So they can handle fast growth without any bottle neck on the Infrastructure and Cloud Platform!

Work Experience

Cloud/DevSecOps/Infrastructure Engineer/Freelance at GBergeret LTD - 06/2020 to now

- Consultant in Public Cloud Help Businesses to migrate from private to public Cloud
- Support Businesses with networking technologies (i.e. VPN) when using public Cloud
- Migrate Infrastructure from Heroku to Docker technologies (i.e. Kubernetes, EKS, GKE)
- Improve CI/CD practice in Businesses so they can ship more reliable code faster
- Deploy Infrastructure as Code and Immutable Infrastructure to improve change process
- Support Businesses with Disaster Recovery policy so data is saved no mater what
- Develop DevSecOps culture so we can apply Security principles from the early stage

Infrastructure Engineer at Fluidly – 01/2019 to 04/2020

- Migrate from Heroku to Google Cloud Platform to host our infrastructure
- Support our mono-environment (no staging, no QA but only 1 environment production)
- Improve CI/CD speed to reduce time to market to less than a day
- Restructured Terraform projects integrate them with the CI/CD pipeline
- Integrate Kapitan and Helm with Terraform projects to manage Kubernetes provisioning
- Develop DevSecOps culture to the whole engineering team

DevOps Engineer at Onfido – 10/2017 to 01/2019

- Initiated GitOps principales from Infrastructure as Code (with Peer Review).
- Implement Jenkins Pipeline integration with terraform to run terraform from Jenkins.
- Integrate Ansible with our Terraform projects to manage OS provisioning.
- Worked on AWS accounts segregation with AWS Organisation (workload segregation).
- Deployed and maintain transit VPC (with datapath.io solution) cross regions and VPCs.

DevOps Engineer at Drivetribe - 11/2016 to 10/2017

- Infrastructure as Code with terraform and ansible (GitOps).
- Move platform to docker infrastructure with Kubernetes as container scheduler.
- Refactoring environments to be easy to run, update and dispose (qa, staging, prod).
- Work around failure points and scalability to be online as much as possible...
- Improve, speed up and stabilise the releasing process.

DevOps Engineer at Onfido – 04/2016 to 11/2016

Education & Training

2015: Master of Science in Computer and Network Engineering (1st class) at ESIPE

Languages Skills

French -> Native

Economy/Finance

English -> Fluent (living in UK from 2015)

Motorcycle

Technical Skills

DevOps: Kubernetes, terraform, test-kitchen, GitOps, CI/CD (Jenkins, CircleCI)

System: Linux, Bash, Ansible, Python, Docker

Infrastructure: AWS, GCP, VPN, Kubernetes (EKS, GKE), Firewall (pfsense, iptables)

Running

Networking: Routing, VRRP, OpenVPN, IPSec, DHCP, DNS **Database**: MERISE, ORM, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Software Developpement: Python, Java, C/C++, Jekyll (Liquid), Git

Management Skills	Project Management	Team organisation	Conduct training
	Independent	Facilitate meeting	Seminar facilitator
Hobbies	Board Games	Cooking	Traveling